(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-02T18:09:54.646045",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
あれ？
Huh?
これ始まっとる？
Is it starting?
始まってる…！
It's started...!
やあ！
Yay!
みなさま、こんばんはする！
Good evening, everyone!
プロライブ参戦白銀ノエルです！
It's Shirogane Noel, here for 3D debut, part three!
いやなんか、みんな！
Hey, everyone!
3Dなんか久しぶりな感じしないけどね。
It's been a while since we did 3D, right?
みんな、こんばんはする！
Good evening, everyone!
なんと！本日はデビュー開始から1周年でございます！
Today is the 1st anniversary of my debut!
ここですね。
Right here!
あの、オークさんも、え？待って、オークさんも1周年を？
Wait, the ogre-san too...?
あれ、待って、オークさん…？って書いてあるけど。
Wait, "ogre-san"...?
オークさん見当たらん。
Wait, where's the ogre-san?
待って、なんでオークさんって書いてんだよ！
Wait, why does it say "ogre-san"?!
なんかダイジンさんがオークみたいになってるじゃん。
Wait, the Daigin-san looks like an ogre...
えっと、これはな、さっき、今の話聞かなかっ…！
Anyway, that didn't make sense just now!
今の話聞かなかったことで、まあダイジンさんもいっぱい来てくれてありがとうございます！
So thank you all Daigin-sans for coming!
もししかしたら最後に歌っちゃったり色々するかもしれないので、最後まで見てくれると嬉しいです！
Maybe some of you might sing at the end, so I'd be happy if you stayed till the end!
よろしくお願いします！
Nice to meet you!
ちなみにね、ハッシュタグはこちら。
Also, the hashtag is...
この白銀ノエル1周年でいっぱいツイートしてくださると…
this Shirogane Noel 1st Anniversary tag!
あとに、団長えら呼吸しに行くので…いっぱ、火じゃない！
Wait, fire? No!
1周年あふれんばかりのありがとう！
Thanks for 1st anniversary!
あふれんばかり、ありがとうございます。
Thanks for everything!
まあ、もししかしたら、まあね、なんだろう、これ「オークさん」って言ったけど…
And you know...
団長ね、あの昨日カウントダウンで、あの初配信の振り返りをしたときに、ちょっとそれを見てくれた人はね、ちょっとお気づきかと思うんですけど、団長実は、今は「ダイジンさん」で、あの、白銀聖騎士団のね「ダイジンさん」ってなってるけど、
Dancho actually... wait, right now you're Daigin-sans, of the Shirogane Seikidan...
もししかしたらワンチャンね、みんなオークになるかもしれなかったからね！
Maybe everyone might become orcs one day, right?
だから、ちょっと、ひとことではないのですが…
So, well, metaphorically speaking, but...
まあ、みんなはね、あの、ダイジンさんなんで、いや、ありがとうございます！
Everyone is a "Daigin-san," so thank you!
あ、いっぱいスーパーチャットもありがと！
And thanks for all the super chats!
なんかね、今日は色々てんこもりで、なんかね、あの、団長が1周年っていうのも、まあそうなんですけど…
Today, you know, everything's a bit chaotic.
今日は、あくあ先輩の2周年だったり、トワちゃんの誕生日だったりも、すごいね、幸せ、しかも親子高校の日でもあるので…
Today is also Aqua-senpai's 2nd anniversary, and Towa-chan's birthday, so it's a super happy day!
いや、なんかすごいね、幸せな日だなと思います。
Yeah, it feels like such a happy day.
昨日はね、フレアのデビュー日だったんで。
Yesterday was Flare's debut day.
そうなんです、そうなんです。
That's right, that's right.
いや本当に、なんかみんな、あ、ありがとうございます！
Yeah, really, everyone... ah, thank you!
なんか、なんだろう、普段さ、普段、普通に、なんだろう、まあ団長、こんな感じ、いつもは…
Usually, normally...
団長いつもはね、こう座って、配信しとるときはこう、こうやって配信しとるから、こうやっていつも揺れながら配信しとるから、なんか体を動かしながら配信するっていうのは、やっぱりなんか新鮮な感じするんですけど…
Well, Daigin always sits and streams, but right now I'm standing and streaming, swaying the whole time.
いや、本当に、ありがとうございま、みんな、ありがとー！ぐぎーす！
Yeah, really, thank you everyone, yay!
ちょっとね、MSR椅子があるんですが。
Wait, there's a MSR chair.
いや、本当に、ありがとうございます。
Yeah, truly, thank you very much.
や、どうしようかな。まあ、今日、ちなみにこの衣装、まあ、普通の衣装なんですけど…
So what should I do? Today, by the way, this outfit is just a regular outfit.
あの、もししかしたらね、後半、あの、今年の1月24日に来た衣装を、もししかしたら見れるかもしれないんで、あの、それまで見てくださると嬉しいです！あ、みんなも、ありがとう、カラフル！
Um, if possible, in the second half, maybe we can see the outfit from January 24th this year, so I'd be happy if you stayed until then! Oh, everyone, thank you, colorful!
すっげえカラフルだ！
Super colorful!
ありがとう！1周年、ありがとうございます！
Thank you! 1st anniversary, thank you very much!
いやね、団長ね、実はちょっと、次のコーナーが…
Yeah, Dancho, actually, the next corner...
あれなんだよな、ちょっと結構きついコーナーで、ちょっと行こうかね、溜めとるんよ。
is, you know, kind of a tough corner, and I've been saving it!
どうにかこうにかこうやって、こう身を伸ばして…
So somehow I'll stretch and relax.
習らんかな。
Let's learn it!
でも先に、どうしようかな。多分、あいとる？、ちょこっと先にね、じゃあちょっと、これ、えっと、こう、なんか今日今朝、
Wait, first, what should I do? Probably, wait, let's do this first!
あのここ会長
Um, President Coco...
どうなんかね、Discord、あの、チャットしとったんやけど
Well, you know, we were chatting on Discord,
なんか、3Dでやってほしいことがあって、ちょっと、やっていい？これ
and there's something I want you to do in 3D, so... can I do this?
みんな、このポーズどう思う？
Everyone, what do you think of this pose?
なんかここ会長いわくガチマタは女の子のポーズで可愛いポーズって言っとったんやけど
Coco-kaichou said 'gachimata' (splayed legs) is a cute girl's pose,
私、どこまで行こっかな？
How far should I go?
どこまで行ける？
How far can I go?
いや、ここは限界かな？
I guess this is my limit?
ここが痛い
My legs hurt...
ここが限界
This is the limit!
なんか、まあ、そんな感じで、ちょっとスクリーンショットしてくれたら
So anyway, if you could take a screenshot,
つぶやいてくれたら嬉しいです。では、
and tweet it, I'd be happy. Now,
そんな感じで、ちょっと、さすがに愛嬌を伸ばしても始まらないんでな
With that said, honestly, dragging out the chitchat won't get us started,
男女後半のね、その、1月24日に来たあの衣装を着たいので、次のコーナー
and since I want to wear that outfit from Jan 24th for the second half, I want to move to the next corner,
行きたいと思います。ちょっと首たくたになっちゃうかも
so I'd like to go. My neck might get stiff though,
しれないんですけど、それでは最初の方、行きます！どーん！
who knows, but let's go to the first corner! Boom!
はい！まっする！ガチ筋トレ！
Yes! Muscle! Hardcore Muscle Training!
あの、まあ「本気」と書いて「ガチ」と読む。今日はね3Dでガチ筋トレをしたいと思います。
Um, reading 'honki' (serious) as 'gachi'. Today I want to do hardcore muscle training in 3D.
いや、なんだろ？
Wait, why?
いや、前回VRホラーでさ、なんか、ヒーヒー言ったのに
Last time in VR horror, I was gasping and panting,
今回は、体力をね、鍛えようと。
so this time, I want to train my stamina.
前回はVRホラーで、精神力がね、鍛えられたんで、
Last time my mental strength was trained in VR horror,
今回はフィジカル！フィジカルで頑張っていこうと思います。
so this time, physical! I'm going to do my best physically.
だんちょ、今日なら何でもできる気がする！
Dancho feels like she can do anything today!
ただ、あの、ちょっと、い、先に言い訳しとくね。
However, um, let me make an excuse beforehand.
先に言い訳しとくけど、だんちょね、1年前よりも体力は落ちたと思う。
I'll make an excuse first, but I think Dancho's stamina has dropped compared to a year ago.
なんか、ね、なんか、やっぱり1年間ね、そう、ホロライブデビューして1年間、えー、なんだろうな、外に出た回数が圧倒的に減ったんだよね。
You know, having debuted in Hololive for a year now, the number of times I went outside dropped overwhelmingly.
圧倒的に減りもしてな、そう、圧倒的に減って、なんか、ちょっと体がなまってる気がするんだよね。
It decreased overwhelmingly, and I feel like my body has gotten a bit out of shape.
まあ、でもだんちょですからね、大丈夫です！交換だと思う。
Well, but I'm Dancho, so it's fine! I think it'll be fine.
まあ、なんでね、筋トレするかっていうと、あのね、初配信でだんちょ、筋トレ、なんか3Dになっちゃったらちょっと筋トレとかしちゃいたいな、みたいな、意気ってて、
Well, why I'm doing muscle training is because in my first stream, I blustered that once I got into 3D, I wanted to do some muscle training,
あ、ちなみにちょっと、だんちょ今日ね、あの、これ、ん？これ薬指か？ちょ薬指がちょっと主張しちゃうんですけど、
Oh, by the way, today... wait, is this my ring finger? My ring finger's kind of standing out,
いや、ほんとになんか、初配信の時にいっぱい筋トレしたいって言ったので、ちょっとそれを実現したいなと思います。
I really said during my first stream that I wanted to do lots of muscle training, so I want to make that a reality.
では、早速やりますか。
Well, shall we do it right away?
いや、できるかな？もうすでにさ、こ、こんなことしてる時点でも息切れするんだけど。行くか。じゃあ、やります。
Can I do it? Even just doing this stuff makes me breathless already. Let's go. Okay, I'll do it.
じゃあ、まずは、どれかな？まず、あ、お題！そうだ、お題プリーズミー！よろしくお願いします。
Well, first, which one? First, oh, topic! That's right, topic please! Please take care of it.
はい、ガチ筋トレメニュー、腕立て伏せ15回！
Yes, hardcore muscle training menu, push-ups 15 times!
あの、これ多分「15回」って言った時に鼻で笑った、ラインさんもいるかと思うんだけど、
Um, I think some people on LINE/viewers laughed through their nose when I said '15 times',
今のだんちょは、まあ、いろいろね、ちょっとやっぱり緊張もしてるし、やっぱ慣れない環境での腕立てなんでね、ちょっと、
but right now Dancho is, well, various things, a bit nervous, and doing push-ups in an unfamiliar environment, so...
いや、できるかな？じゃあ、早速ちょっと腕立て伏せやろうかな。
Can I do it? Well, let's start push-ups right away.
いや、何ヶ月ぶりだろう？最近筋トレしてないからいっか。よしお。
How many months has it been? I haven't done muscle training lately, so whatever. Okay.
え、じゃあこれもう始めちゃっていいんですか？
Eh, so can I just start this now?
はい！よーし、行きます！12345678910...
Yes! Alright, let's go! 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10...
これ本当に殺しにしがみかかってますよね。
This is really trying to kill me.
これさ、ちょっと待って、リハの時でもこれ牛丼落ちますよって言われたんだけど、これ殺しに...
Wait a minute, during rehearsal they said 'gyudon will drop even then', but this is to kill...
あ、これご褒美ですか？あ、ありがとうございます。消された。
Ah, is this a reward? Ah, thank you. Deleted.
すいません。はい、真面目にします。
Sorry. Yes, I'll take it seriously.
いや、本当にさ、あれ、頭落ちたら死ぬで、普通に。
Seriously, if my head drops, I'd die normally.
じゃあ、ちゃんと真面目にしたいと思います。では、行きます！
Well, I want to do it properly and seriously. Now, let's go!
1、2、3、4、5、6、7、8、9、10、11、12、13、14、15！
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15!
はや！
Haah!
今のはいいの？やったぞ。
Was that good? I did it.
あ、ちょっと、あ、足が、やりましたが。
Ah, wait, ah, my legs... I did it.
あ、お水。あ、合格やった！
Ah, water. Ah, I passed, yay!
やりました。ちょっとみんな、どういうアングルでちょっと映っとったんか？
I did it. Hey everyone, what kind of angle was I filmed from?
だんちょ真剣にやったからミートランキングしたからアングルで。
Because Dancho did it seriously...
みんなもいい、いい感じ？いい感じだった？
Was it good for you guys too, good feeling? Was it a good feel?
うん、顎は埋行くの。
Yeah, my chin is buried in the mic.
やばい、ガチ筋トレの人に怒られとる。
Oh no, I'm getting yelled at by hardcore muscle training people.
よし、いや、まだまだ続くからね。いや、まだ、でもだんちょね、実は腕立てが一番苦手で、
Alright, well, it's still going to continue. Well, still, but actually Dancho, push-ups are my worst...
腕はね、 実は 筋肉 あれなんですよ。
Actually, my arms... lack muscle, you see.
ちょっと一時期スクワットばっかしてて、腕の筋肉があまりないの でね、ま、
For a while I was just doing squats, so I don't have much arm muscle, so...
次からは余裕なんじゃないかなと。
I figured the next one would be a breeze.
では次の題、お願いします。どうや？スクワット15回。
So for the next topic, please. How's this? 15 squats.
ああ、スクワットね。ま、スクワットでもスクワットこそね、何が怖いかって、正直できるかできないかよりも、
Ah, squats. Well, when it comes to squats, what's scary isn't really whether I can do them or not...
あれなんだよね、スクワット警察の人が怖い。
It's the "squat police"—they're terrifying.
なんかさ、足が、なんかこう、膝の前に出てるぞみたいな、とかなんか言われそうなんだけど、ちょっとよし、ま、そんなかん、やるか。
Like, they'll point out, "Your knees are sticking out past your toes!" or something... But anyway, let's just do it.
ちょっと団長のスクワットちゃんとできてるかっていうのも、あの、チェックしてください。
Also, please check if Danchou is doing her squats properly.
では、いきます。
Well then, here I go!
よいしょ、
One...
1、
Two...
2、
Three...
3、
Four...
4、
Five...
5、
Six...
6、
Seven...
7、もっと深く！8
Seven... Go deeper! Eight.
もっと、ぐあっ、ぐう
More, ugh, uwaa...
もっと、え、どんだけ、こんなってこと？これ？
More! Wait, how low? Like this?
10... 10、膝曲がって...いや曲がって！やべっ
10... 10, my knees are bending—no, bending! Oh crap...
ほら、これ、これこ、こうですか、先生？
Look, is this—is this how you do it, Sensei?
で、ゆっくり、11
And slowly, 11.
で、ぐわあ！先生、こうですか？一緒になにしてんだなに。こう、こうですか？もっと落として、落とせないよ！
And... Whoa! Sensei, is this right? What am I even doing? Is this it? Drop lower, don't drop!
よし、やばい、ちょっと、うわ！ストイック、ちょっと帽子も貰っちゃった、13
Alright, yikes, whoa! So stoic, I even got a hat. 13...
はあ、スクワットちゃんも、おめでとう誕生日！で、10、よっしゃ、15
Hah, Squat-chan, happy birthday too! And 10, alright, 15—
あ、15じゃねぇな、14か。で、もう1回、15
Ah, not 15, 14. Then once more, 15!
もっとゆっくり上げ。で、もう1回だけ、よし。ちょっとね、団長も負けず嫌いだからね、先生の言われたことを全部やりたい。
Raise it even slower. And just one more time, alright. You see, Danchou hates losing, so I want to do everything Sensei told me.
こうしてゆっくり、うおー、こうですか？
Like this, slowly, uooo... is this it?
どうでしょう？なんか、かっこよくない？ちょっと
How is it? Doesn't it look cool? A bit...
なにこれ、なに帽子？運営さんがやってくれた、ありがとう！嬉しい！祭り先輩みたいなの、ありがとう！祭り先輩も帽子被ってる
What is this hat? Management made this for me, thank you! I'm so happy! Like Matsuri-senpai, thank you! Matsuri-senpai is wearing a hat too.
かっこいい。どうでしょう、今のわ、オッケーですか？
Cool. How was that, is it okay?
オッケーです、やった！ねえそうこと、団長さ、あの剣道現役時代にあれしとった
It's okay, yay! You know what, Danchou used to do that back in her active Kendo days...
これ。これ何これ？このポーズでわかる人いるんかな？こうやって、団長やってたなあ。
This. What is this? Does anyone recognize this pose? Danchou used to do this.
そう、あの、ぶ、ぶ、ぶ、ぶ、キャンプみたいな感じの帽子を、ありがとうございます！
Yeah, that, bu-bu-bu-bu-camp-style hat, thank you so much!
あ、ここ会長！ここ会長も、ありがとう！ちゃんとガニマタしとるで、ありがとう！
Ah, Coco-kaichou! Coco-kaichou too, thank you! Doing proper bowlegs, thank you!
じゃあ、次、行きますか？じゃあ、次のお題を、どん！空気椅子20秒。
Well then, shall we go to the next one? Next topic, boom! 20 seconds of air chairs.
あ、これさ、あ、団長ね、20秒と言わず、何秒でもできるよ。よしよし、いきますね。
Ah, this, well, Danchou can do it not just for 20 seconds, but any amount of time. Alright, here we go.
これ団長ね、姿勢めっちゃぴっとるで、ふん。
Danchou's posture is super straight here, hum.
ほら、すごくない？ほら。うーん、椅子の音聞こえませんよ、ちょっと運営さんに言われた気がするけど。ううん、どこのが、しごくにいんか。
Look, isn't this amazing? Look. Hmm, you can't hear any chair sounds, I feel like management told me. Well, where is it, hell?
いやなんか足上がっとるな。いやそんなこっち怒られそうだから。おおいおいおいおい！あ、ちょっと椅子、待ってください！
Wait, my legs are going up. Well, I might get scolded for that. Hey hey hey hey! Ah, wait, chair, hold on!
椅子用意されたらさ、ほんとに座ってるみたいになっちゃうじゃん。じゃあガチでね、じゃあガチでやります。
If an air chair is prepared, it'll look like I'm actually sitting. Alright, let's do this seriously.
よし。よしやります。ちょっと今ね、運営さんがちょっと不正を暴こうとしたのを、団長はスルーしてやろうと思います。
Alright. Alright, I'll do it. You see, management tried to expose some cheating just now, but Danchou is going to ignore it.
空気椅子ってどんな感じなのだろう？ちょっとやってみます。これこうして
What does an air chair feel like? Let's try it. Like this...
こうか？こういうこと？あ、ちょっと待って、ほい。はい、あ、秒数。
Like this? Is this it? Ah, wait, ho. Yes, ah, counting seconds.
ええと、1、2、3、4、5、6、7、8、9、もっと深く！づあっ！
Uh, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, deeper! Zua!
あ、で、これ確かにこう言うこと？あ、優雅に。で、11、12、13、14、もっと、15、16、17、18、19、え、待って、もっと深くっ！
Ah, and this is really what it means? Ah, gracefully. Then 11, 12, 13, 14, more, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19... wait, even deeper!
本当こうなっちゃう。
Seriously, I end up like this.
いやもう、死んじゃうよ！死んじゃうよ！
No, I'm gonna die! I'm gonna die!
なんどうですか？足くぼ。待って。
How is it? My legs are shaking. Wait.
こういうこと？ いや、無理だよ！
Like this? No way, that's impossible!
無理に無理！
No way, impossible!
いち、
One,
に、
two,
さん、
three,
し、
four,
ご、
five,
ろく、
six,
しち、
seven,
はち、
eight,
きゅう、
nine,
じゅう、
ten,
じゅういち、
eleven,
じゅうに、
twelve,
じゅうさん、
thirteen,
じゅうし、
fourteen,
じゅうご、
fifteen,
じゅうろく、
sixteen,
じゅうしち、
seventeen,
じゅうはち、
eighteen,
じゅうく、
nineteen,
にじゅう！
twenty!
命！
My life!
なに、合格？
What, I passed?
いや、これで合格じゃなかったらだんちょーもう、もうだんちょー引退だよ！
If this isn't passing, Danchou's retiring right now!
よかった。
Thank goodness.
いや本当ガチ筋トレになって、あ、ありがとうございます。
Seriously, this became a hardcore workout. Ah, thanks.
お水をいただいてな。よいしょ。
Let me have some water. Heave-ho.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
よしっ、じゃあ
Alright, then...
次で最後かな。
This might be the last one.
次で最後なんですけど、だんちょーね、正直これが一番キツイと思うんだよね。
It's the last one, but honestly, Danchou thinks this is the toughest.
じゃあちょっと次のメニュー、いきます！ ドン！
So let's go to the next menu! Boom!
ガチ筋トレメニュー、プランク30秒。
Hardcore workout menu: Plank for 30 seconds.
30秒！
30 seconds!
これやばいんじゃないか？プランクっていうのはこうやってね、体幹を鍛えるんだけど、いや正直ね、プランクはマジでキツイ。
Isn't this dangerous? Planks are for core training, but honestly, they're tough.
からどうなんだろうと、でもみんなもするんだよ、みんなも。
I wonder how it affects me... but everyone does it too.
なんか「腰をもっと深く落とすんだよ」とか言ってたけど、みんなもするんだよ、みんなも！ライバーさんなんだから、だんちょーがこんな頑張ってんだからね！
People said "lower your hips," but everyone does it! Danchou is working hard!
よし、では行きますか？よし。
Alright, shall we go? Okay.
はあ、いけるかな？はあ。
Whew, can I do this? Whew.
いや違うんだ、みんなね余裕っていっていくけど、だんちょーね、あの人よりもちょっとお荷物を、お荷物つけてっから、ね、ハンデが
Everyone says it's easy, but Danchou is carrying extra baggage, so there's a handicap...
ありますからね。では行きます！
So there is. Now let's go!
いち、
One,
に、
two,
さん、
three,
し、
four,
ご、
five,
ろく、
six,
なな、
seven,
はち、
eight,
きゅう、
nine,
じゅう、
ten,
じゅういち、
eleven,
じゅうに、
twelve,
じゅうさん、
thirteen,
じゅうし、
fourteen,
じゅうご、
fifteen,
じゅうろく、
sixteen,
じゅうしち、
seventeen,
じゅうはち、
eighteen,
じゅうく、
nineteen,
にじゅう、
twenty,
にじゅういち、
twenty-one,
にじゅうに、
twenty-two,
にじゅうさん、
twenty-three,
にじゅうし、
twenty-four,
にじゅうご、
twenty-five,
にじゅうろく、
twenty-six,
にじゅうしち、
twenty-seven,
にじゅうはち、
twenty-eight,
にじゅうく、
twenty-nine,
さんじゅう！
thirty!
あれ？
Huh?
結構いける！
I'm doing pretty well!
え、まだ20秒？嘘でしょ？
Wait, only 20 seconds? You've got to be kidding me!
もう終わると思ったから余裕って言ったのに、何がうえさん20秒だよ、できるわけなかろうが！
I said it was easy thinking it was almost over, what do you mean 20 more seconds!
いや、あびゃー！
Aww, abya~!
あ、牛丼、牛丼！あ、あ、向こういっちゃった。
Ah, gyudon, gyudon! Ah, it went over there.
いや、だんちょーにとって、いや、牛丼で潰されて死ねるなら本望だよ！
Dying crushed under gyudon would be fulfilling!
はあ、ありがとうございます。
Whew, thank you very much.
え、皆さんどうですか？どう、ちなみにどう、どうでした？筋トレ。
Everyone, how is it? How was the workout?
まあ、今多分ね、心臓の聞いたらすごいことなると思います、心臓。
If you checked my heart right now, it'd be crazy.
だんちょーが筋トレしてるのそばで、え、ちょ、なに？だんちょー、だんちょーが筋トレしてるのを見ながら食べるご飯は美味しいわ！ふざけんな！やるんだよ！やれ！
Eating food while watching Danchou work out is delicious?! Do it!
やるんだよ！やんな！
Do it! Do it!
いや、ありがとうございます。いや、なんか、はあ、息がぜぇぜぇ。
Ah, thank you. Man, I'm panting so hard.
まあね、ま、だんちょー今の時点ではこんな感じ。まあ一応クリアはできたけど、正直ね、ま、体まだまだ訛ってんね。
I managed to clear it, but my body's still pretty rusty.
なので、ちょっと来週ね、ちょっとだんちょーリングフィットアドベンチャーを再開しますんで、もし筋トレ好きな人とかだんちょーがヒュウヒュウ鳴るところ見たい方はぜひぜひそちらも見てください。
So next week Danchou is resuming Ring Fit, so please check it out!
昭和の動き、昭和の動き？え、これ昭和？昭和じゃないでしょ！
Showa era movements? This isn't Showa!
ありがとうございます。じゃあちょっと他にもね、コーナーがあるので、いや、ま、これでねだんちょーヒュウヒュウになれたと思うので、次のコーナーに行きたいと思います！
I think Danchou got all out of breath from this, let's move on!
では、次のコーナー、どん！
Now, the next corner, boom!
以心伝心3期生クイズ！
Ishin Denshin 3rd Gen Quiz!
イェーイ！なんだ以心伝心3期生クイズって思うと思うんですけど、
Yay! You're probably wondering what that is,
えっとね、ま、デビューからずっと一緒にいるね、ホロライブファンタジー、ホロライブ3期生。だんちょーが3期生のみんなのこと理解できてるかっていうのを
Hololive 3rd Gen have been together since debut. Let's see if Danchou understands everyone...
ちょっと試していこうかなっていうコーナーです。
This is a corner where we'll try things out.
ま、3期生全員にね、クイズの、クイズ、息切れがヤバいな。
Well, quizzes for all 3rd gen members... whew, I'm getting out of breath.
ごめんみんな、聞き取りやすい、意外と息切れしてる。
Sorry everyone, it's easy to hear, I'm surprisingly out of breath.
ま、3期生全員にクイズを回答してもらったので、その答えが4択の中の1つにありますのでね、あの、じゃあそれ当てていこうかなっていう感じです。
Well, all 3rd gen members answered the quiz, and the answer is one of four choices, so... yeah, we'll try to guess that.
ま、正解数に応じて何かしらご褒美があるらしいんで、じゃあ頑張ります。
Well, apparently there's some kind of reward depending on the number of correct answers, so I'll do my best.
てごめん、これ薬指だからね、ちょっとごめんね、ちょっと手を、手が薬指曲がくんんだ。頑張ります。
Oh sorry, this is my ring finger, so sorry, my hand... my ring finger won't bend. I'll do my best.
そう、団長らしいコーナー。いや、間違えたらやばいよ！間違えたらどうしよう。
Right, a Dancho-like corner. Man, if I get it wrong, that's bad! What should I do if I get it wrong?
1人いるからね、1人いる、なんかみんな答えられるんじゃないかなと思う。
There's one person, there's one person, I think everyone can probably answer.
だっ、こういうクイズって大体は、ま、大体はさ、私の好きな食べ物は？とか、なんか、逆に嫌いな食べ物は何ペコか？みたいな感じで、そういう
Like, quizzes like this are usually, well, usually like "What is my favorite food?" or something, or conversely "What food do you hate, peko?", something like that...
なんか、普通そうじゃん。そんなね、多分難しくはないんじゃないかなと思うので、
Well, normally it's like that. It probably won't be that difficult, so,
ま、それでは最初の問題に行きたいと思います！では、最初の問題はこちらです！
Well then, let's go to the first question! Now, the first question is right here!
あ、そうだ、移動するのか。トゥットゥッ、あ、えっと、るしあ、最近見た映画は何だ？
Oh right, am I moving? Tututu, ah, um, Rushia, what movie did you see recently?
ちょっと待ってくれ、ちょっと待って、ちょっと待って。
Wait a minute, wait a minute, wait a minute.
最近見た映画は何だ？赤で、え、恋愛、えっと、緑、シリアス、で、青がホラー、で、黄色がドキュメンタリー。ちょっと待って。
What movie did you see recently? Red is romance, um, green is serious, blue is horror, and yellow is documentary. Wait a minute.
これさ、分かるんですかね？これさ、るしあ、るしあね、あれだよ、どんなに団長るしあのこと好きでもさ、るしあがファンデットさんにしてるみたいにね、ベッドの下からこうやって覗いたりしてないんだぞ。ええ？
Do you know this? This... Rushia, Rushia, you know, no matter how much Dancho likes Rushia, she doesn't peek from under the bed like Rushia does to Fandetto-san. Huh?
どれだろう。えっと、で、ま、考えよう。
Which one could it be? Um, well, let's think.
恋愛は、確かにルシア恋愛ドラマ、なんか乙女だけど見ない気がする。ど、みんな、どう思う？そうでしょう？
Romance, certainly Rushia... romance dramas, as a maiden she feels like she doesn't watch them. What do you all think? Right?
性格的に恋愛というよりも、恋愛よりもファンタジーとかが好きだから、恋愛はペ、ペして、
Personality-wise, rather than romance, she likes fantasy and stuff more, so romance is... bleh, scratch that,
で、シリアスはシリアスってどんなの？シリアスって、シリアス？
And serious... what is a serious movie like? Serious? Serious?
いや、難しい。シリアスな映画は難しいからぺ。
No, it's difficult. Serious movies are difficult, so bleh.
で、ホラーは毎回見てるから、多分ホラーなんじゃないかな？ホラー、で、ホラーなんじゃないかなと思うし、
And horror, she watches every time, so maybe it's horror? Horror, well, I think it might be horror, and
次、え、ドキュメンタリー。ちょっと待って、あね、ホラーとドキュメンタリーで今すごい悩んでる。
Next, um, documentary. Wait a minute, um, I'm worrying a lot between horror and documentary right now.
え、待って、悩まさせて。ここ絶対、あのね、これ間違えたらマジでルシアからさ、え？ノエル、私のこと見てないのってガチでね、そう、私、私のこと嫌いなのかなみたいに泣いちゃうからさ、ちょっと真剣に。
Wait, let me worry about it. Here, seriously, um, if I get this wrong, seriously from Rushia... like "Noel, you're not looking at me?" she'll seriously cry like "Ah, do you hate me?", so let me take this seriously.
ドキュメンタリーは、ペット系のドキュメンタリーを見てる気がするけど、でもね、ホラーだと思う。
Documentary... I feel like she watches pet-genre documentaries, but still, I think it's horror.
なんてかっていうと、ルシアはメン限でホラーをよく見てるし、
Why is that? Because Rushia often watches horror on member-only streams,
あの、なんだろうな、団長この前ジオン見た、そうあの、ルシアがなジオンか何かをメン限で見て、なんか、あれジオンだけかな？
um, what was it, Dancho saw Sion recently, yeah um, Rushia watched Shion or something on a member-only stream, and like, was that only Shion?
なんか、貞子？あのビデオのやつ、貞子だっけ？貞子だ、貞子。
Something like Sadako? That video thing, was it Sadako? It's Sadako, Sadako.
貞子見てなんか、その呪われたかもしれないって言ってるのを、団長聞いてるから、
I've heard her say she might have been cursed after watching Sadako,
ホラーで行きます！行きます、ホラーで。
I'll go with horror! I'm going with horror.
じゃあ、団長、ホラーで行きます！よろしくお願いします！どうでしょう？
Well, Dancho, I'll go with horror! Please wish me luck! How is it?
やったーー！
Yay!!
ホラー！みんな、これが3期生の絆だよ。
Horror! Everyone, this is the bond of the 3rd generation.
でも結構みんな分かっ、あれリングかリング？あ、ちょっと、あれ、映画までは分からんかったけど。
Though everyone pretty much understood... was that Ring or Ring? Ah, well, I didn't get up to the movie itself though.
そうなんだ、やった！とりあえず刺されることはなくなったぞ。ルシア見とるか？団長当てたぞ！当てたぞ！
Is that so, yay! At least I won't get stabbed anymore. Are you watching, Rushia? Dancho guessed it! I guessed it!
当てたぞ！ま、やっぱホラーが好きなんだね。いや、意外とルシアね強、待て待て待て待て！
I guessed it! Well, after all, she loves horror. Man, surprisingly Rushia is str... wait wait wait wait!
なんて、あ、ご褒美ですか、これ？ど、どういう意味で落としたんです？
What, ah, is this a reward? Wh-what do you mean by dropping it?
あ、ご褒美ですか、ちょっと待って。いや、もっとご褒美の落とし方ちゅうもんがね、あると、思うんですけど。
Ah, is it a reward? Wait a minute. Well, I think there's a better way to drop a reward.
ありがとうね、じゃあ、あむあむあむあむあむ。美味しい！あむあむあむあむあむ。ありがとうございます！
Thank you, well, *nom nom nom*. Delicious! *nom nom nom*. Thank you very much!
じゃあ、次に行くか。これをね、あれ、あれかな、1問ごとに1個降ってくるんだったら、じゃあ4個食べれるかもしれないのか。
Well, shall we go to the next one? If one drops for every question, then maybe I can eat four of them.
じゃあ、4個制覇するぞという気持ちで、次の問題行きたいと思います！どん！
Well, with the feeling of conquering all four, let's go to the next question! Boom!
ええと、マリンからの出題です。ええ、船長へ、ノエルのどこが一番好きでしょうか？
Um, this is a question from Marin. Uh, to Senchou: What part of Noel do you like the most?
赤、性格。緑、胸。
Red: Personality. Green: Breasts.
青、太陽系デスコの「せい！」。黄色、顔。えー…
Blue: "Sei!" from Taiyoukei Desco. Yellow: Face. Uh...
これさ、いや、悩んでるよ。
This... well, I'm agonizing over this.
いやでもね、マリンは団長の性格いいって言ってくれるよ。
But you know, Marine always says the chieftain has a great personality.
え、こんなか、いや性格かもくんないな。
Well, out of these... maybe it's personality?
いや性格であってほしいって（笑）思うんだけど、
Well, I kind of *want* it to be personality (laughs),
なんだろう、うーん。
but what could it be? Hmm.
なんか性格は、なんだろう、「優しいね」っていつも言ってくれる。優しい。で、
She always says, "You're so kind." Kind. And...
あの、緑...そ、胸。
Uh, green... right, breasts.
え、確かにね、あの、お風呂であったときにいつも触らせてくださいって言うけど（笑）
Well, it's true, whenever we take a bath together, she's always like, "Let me touch them," (laughs)
「触らせて」って言うけど、
saying "Let me touch,"
えでもね、いや逆に一番ではないと思うの。
but you know, I don't think it's number one, actually.
うん、一番じゃない。なんか、
Yeah, not number one. It's like...
で、あの、この青の太陽系デスコの「せい」はめちゃくちゃ言われてるの。
And, uh, this blue one, the "fault" in Solar System Disco, gets brought up *so* much.
これめちゃくちゃ、あの団長がね、歌下手なんだ けど恥ずかしいなって言ったときに、
This is because whenever the chieftain says, "Man, I'm bad at singing this,"
いや、団長は、ノールの太陽系デスコの「せい」が好きですね！やって！あれやって！って何回もやらされてるから、
Marine's like, "No, Chieftain, I love Noel's 'fault' in Solar System Disco! Do it! Do it!" and makes me do it over and over.
これか。で、顔は、でも、顔はね、なんだろうね。
So this? And face... well, face is, I wonder.
正直胸しか見てねえから、見てねえと思うんだよ（笑）
Honestly, she only looks at my boobs, so I bet she doesn't even look at my face (laughs).
だからマリン、顔、団長の顔見てないよ。あんまり顔、顔言われたことない。胸ばっか言われるから、
So Marine doesn't look at my face. She hardly ever mentions my face. People only talk about my boobs,
じゃあちょっと、え、みんなはどう思う？みんなは。
so... what do you guys think? Everyone?
みんな的にどうも、団長は、ま、クイズの法則で、この、なん だ、すごく具体的に書いてるやつが正解なんではって思うんだけど、
Everyone-wise, like, following quiz logic, I'd think the one written with such specific detail would be the correct answer, but...
みんなの意見聞こうかな、今回は。（笑）ね、胸っ（笑）
let's hear everyone's opinion this time (laughs). Right, boobs (laughs).
ちょっとこれみんなの意見じゃねえんだぞ。な、これみんなのさ、ちょっと本音が漏れたんじゃないか。
Wait, this isn't everyone's opinion, is it? Hey, didn't everyone's true feelings leak out here?
そのマリンのさ、答えにしようとしてるけど、みんなが好きなんでしょ？
You're trying to make it Marine's answer, but you guys just like it, right?
ちょ見ないでください。見てください、そうやって。
Please don't look. Look at me like that.
もう、団長のこと何見てんだよ。顔より胸の方がでかいから胸に、
Jeez, what are you even looking at? My boobs are bigger than my face, so you talk about my boobs—
胸に話しかけてます。おい、マリン！もうちょっと見ないでください！
talking to my boobs. Hey, Marine! Stop looking there!
目、目を見てよ、目！
Look me in the eye, my eyes!
何コミュ障みたいなことしてんだ。ちょっともっと（笑）
Why are you acting like you have social anxiety? Come on... (laughs)
え、じゃあ、え団長、う、
Uh, well... Chieftain, uh...
いや、青だ と思うんだけど、でもみんなが胸って言うから、団長自信なくなってきた。団長胸だけのおんなかもしれないから、
Well, I think it's blue, but everyone keeps saying boobs, so the Chieftain is losing confidence. Maybe I'm just a woman with only boobs...
ちょっと緑にしようかな。いや、自信も、したい。
so maybe I'll go with green. No, I want confidence.
自信、いや、胸にする！いや、自信ない。
Confidence— no, I'll go with boobs! No, I have no confidence.
胸、これにするわ。うん。いや、じゃあ胸にする。胸。
Boobs, I'll go with this. Yeah. No, then I'll choose boobs. Boobs.
じゃあ、どうですか？うえさん、団長、（笑）だろうな（笑）
So, how about it? Uei-san, Chieftain... (laughs) figures (laughs).
ああ、自分、信じればよかった！もっと、もっとさ、自分の魅力を自信付ければよかった！
Ah, I should've believed in myself! I should have had more confidence in my own charm!
最近自分胸だけしかねえのか とか思ってたから（笑）ああ！
Lately I've been thinking I'm all about boobs (laughs). Ah!
マリン、あ、じゃあちょっとマリンのためにね、ちょっと間違えちゃったけど、じゃあマリンの、マリンに送る。
Marine, ah, well, for Marine's sake... I messed up, but okay, I'll send this to Marine.
じゃあマリンの好きな、じゃあ、やりますね。「きらめいて☆彡」
Then, for Marine's favorite... okay, I'll do it. "Kirameite ☆彡"
あ、もう（笑）せっかちおじさん（笑）いる（笑）
Ah, jeez (laughs), impatient old man (laughs) is here (laughs).
これだ、なの肩！（笑）え、すげえ！もらった、これ！
This is it, nano-kata! (laughs) Wow, amazing! I got this!
一体けど、やった！あむあむ！やった！
I did it! Nom nom! Yay!
ありがとう！やった、これお情けでもらっちった。すげえバランスがいいよ。（笑）
Thank you! Yay, I got this out of pity. The balance is amazing. (laughs)
瞬発、瞬発、
Quick, quick—
あ、おも、おもっ、ちょ、さすがに重いよ（笑）
ah, heavy, heavy, wait, it's actually heavy (laughs).
重いよ、おもた（笑）
It's heavy, so heavy (laughs).
はあ、これはまあ、あれだね、これ間違えたのはリスナーさんのせいでもあるからね。（笑）リスナーさんのせいでもある。
Whew, well, this is... you know, getting this wrong is partly the listeners' fault too (laughs). Partly the listeners' fault.
じゃあ次こっか。じゃあそんな感じで次当てるぞ。
Well, next up. Alright, with that in mind, I'm gonna get the next one right.
じゃあ次の問題、ドン！不知火フレアが一番好きと配信で言っているケーキの名前は？
Next question, boom! What is the name of the cake Shiranui Flare says is her absolute favorite on stream?
おフレアな！フレア！えっと、赤ブッシュ・ド・ノエル、えっと、緑フォンダン・ショコラ、青、ハシュ、じゃ、ザッハトルテ、
Oh, Flare! Flare! Um, red is Bûche de Noël, um, green is fondant au chocolat, blue, hash— wait, Sachertorte,
で、黄色がハッシュ・ド・ノエル。
and yellow is Hash de Noel.
あんさあ...（笑） 団長引っかかると思った？これ。
You see... (laughs) Did you think the Chieftain would fall for this? This.
ねえ！これあれでしょ？ブッシュ・ド・ノエルとハッシュ・ド・ノエルって言ってさ、あ、ノエルのこと好きなんですねって言ってほしいやつでしょ？ねえ！これ団長知ってるよ。
Hey! This is that, right? Saying Bûche de Noël and Hash de Noel, hoping I'd say, "Oh, you must really like Noel, right?" Right! The Chieftain knows this.
もう団長なん、こう、ねえ、もう1一緒にいるからさ、こんなの... あの、ちょっと運営さんこれ選択肢間違えましたね。
Chieftain has been together for a year now, so stuff like this... Uh, management, you got the choices wrong here.
団長は、団長だけのノエルを好きって言ってほしい。
The Chieftain wants you to say you love Noel and *only* Noel.
ブッシュ・ド・ノエルだったらめちゃブッシュ・ド・ノエルに嫉妬するし、
If it's Bûche de Noël, I'd be super jealous of Bûche de Noël,
人に嫉妬する。だから団長は
People get jealous of others. So Danchou
フォンダンショコラかザッハトルテなんだけど、
guessed fondant au chocolat or Sachertorte,
これちょっとガチでいきます。
but I'm going to get serious about this.
すみません、これね団長問答無用でザッハトルテだと思う。
I'm sorry, but Danchou has no doubt it's Sachertorte.
みんなはどうでしょう？
What do you all think?
ショコラかな？あ、みんなしょこ、フォンダンショコラだと思う。
Is it chocolat? Ah, everyone thinks fondant au chocolat.
結構フレア、ザッハトルテって言ってるよ。
Flare actually says Sachertorte a lot.
そう、配信でも言ってるし、裏でもねザッハトルテって言ってて、
Yeah, she says it on streams, and behind the scenes too,
なんか前に、コンビニかどっか行った時にもザッハトルテって、ザッハトルテ好きなんだって言ってるの、
and once when we went to a convenience store she said she loves Sachertorte.
団長聞いたので。
Danchou heard her.
じゃあザッハトルテお願いします！
So, Sachertorte, please!
イェーイ！
Yay!
そう、ザッハトルテ。でも結構みんな
Right, Sachertorte. But pretty much everyone
知ってたね。
knew it, huh?
ザッハトルテって何なんだ？なんかチョコの方？
What even is Sachertorte? Is it the chocolate kind?
わかんない、団長ね正直ねフォンダンショコラとザッハトルテ見た目、なんかなんだろう、
I don't know, honestly Danchou thinks fondant au chocolat and Sachertorte look...
ツルツルしとる？あ、チョコでコーティングされとるなんか、みたいな感じ、
shiny? Ah, coated in chocolate or something, kind of like that,
なんですよな。そう。
you know. Yeah.
いやこれはね、
Well, this was
余裕のよっちゃんでした。
an easy win.
余裕のよっちゃんっつか、さっすがの！あー！フレア！フレア見るか！
An easy win, or rather... As expected! Ah—! Flare! Flare, look!
おおいおいおい！
Hey, hey, hey!
ま、一応ねいまんとこちょっとマリンのはちょっと自分の自信のなさで外してしまったけど、
Well, for now Marine's answer was wrong due to lack of confidence, but...
まあ、
well,
あ、これご褒美か。
Ah, is this a reward?
ちょっと、ご褒美がいっいつもなんかぶっそ
Wait, Danchou's rewards are always so ominous—
だって時速さ200kmとか300kmぐらいでぴょんって落ちてくる。あ、ありがとスパチャ、ありがと！ノエルではガチ。
I mean, falling at 200 or 300 km/h... Ah, thanks for the Superchat, thanks! For Noel, it's serious.
ということで、じゃあ最後の問題ですね、いきますか。
With that, let's move on to the final question!
それでは、最後の問題はなんとぺこらっちゅんなんですけど、
Now then, the final question is about Pekorat...chu,
なんかね、ぺこらっちゅを
and it seems Pekorat...chu...
なんかね、すごいポエムっぽいのをちょっと、なんかポエムっぽいやつを問題にしたらしくて、ちょっと団長読ませていただきます。
apparently made something very poem-like into a question, so let Danchou read it out.
では、いきます！
Now then, here we go!
いつもひとりぼっちだった。
It was always lonely.
そんな時に君が現れた。
That was when you appeared.
なんかいかにも弱そうでぺこらでも倒せそうな君。
Someone who looked so weak that even Pekora could defeat you.
一緒に日々を過ごしていた。
We spent our days together.
とある日いじわる小僧たちが君をいじめていた。
One day, some mean little brats were bullying you.
ぺこらは見てみぬふりをしてしまった。
Pekora pretended not to see.
ごめんね、あの時見捨てちゃって、けどもう逃げない。
I'm sorry for abandoning you back then, but I won't run away anymore.
お前を強くするのはこの私だ！！
It is I who will make you strong!!
なんだこれ？
What is this?
はい、これなんでしょう、何を読まされてんだ団長。
Yeah, what is this, what is Danchou being made to read?
てことで、問題文があるんですね。お、きた。
So there's a question text. Oh, it's here.
じゃあぺこらっちゅの問題です。最後の問題。これはなんの配信の時のポエムでしょうか？
Now, it's Pekorat...chu's question. The final question. What stream's poem is this?
赤が7月17日の勇なま。
Red is July 17th's Yuunama.
で、緑が7月14日のやるドラ。
Green is July 14th's Yarudora.
で、青が7月3日のモンスターファーム。
Blue is July 3rd's Monster Farm.
で、黄色が7月17日の一周年記念。
Yellow is July 17th's 1st Anniversary.
いや、これはさ、
Man, this is...
これさ、あのね、ポエムの内容から考えてみよ。団長正直、ぺこらのポエムは全部同じ。
Let's think about this from the poem's content. Honestly, all of Pekora's poems are the same.
なんか、また、また悟ってんなって思いながらさ、いつも、なんかこう聞き逃がしとる、なんか聞き逃がしとるから、ちょっとどれかわからんなあ。
Thinking "Ah, she's having another epiphany," and always missing parts of it, so I'm not sure which one it is.
ぺこら、ぺこらっちゅのツイート見てんだけど、まず、
I'm looking at Pekorat...chu's tweet, but first,
弱虫なんだよ。
it's a weakling.
弱虫、弱い、でいじめられてる。
Weakling, weak, being bullied.
で、でもぺこら、ぺこらっちゅは、その子を強くする、もう逃げない。
But Pekorat...chu will make that kid strong, won't run away anymore.
この4つ。
These four.
っていうと、
That being said,
やるドラは絶対違う。やるドラのストーリーでは全然違うね。
Yarudora is definitely different. Yarudora's story is totally different.
そうそうそう、やるドラではない。一周年記念も、なんか複数人登場してるし。
Right, right, it's not Yarudora. The 1st Anniversary has multiple people appearing too.
ぺこらっちゅの一周年なのに、誰、誰がいじめられてんだみたいな。これはノウサギさんに向けた言葉なのかってなっちゃうから、
Even though it's Pekorat...chu's anniversary, who's getting bullied? It makes you wonder if it's words directed at Nousagi-san,
一周年じゃないっていうことは、
which means it's not the anniversary,
二つに絞られるんだけど、団長は実はモンスターファーム
so it narrows down to two, but Danchou actually... Monster Farm...
あの、知ってるんですよ。
I know about it.
その、モンスターファームね、一時期実況とか色々見てたりするから、
Because for a while I watched let's plays and stuff of Monster Farm,
モンスターファームってそういう感じだったよね。
Monster Farm was kind of like that, right?
そう。だからみんなモンスターファームだと思うんだけど、どうでしょう？
Yeah. So everyone probably thinks Monster Farm, but what do you think?
みんな、モンファっぽいよね。ぽいよね、ぽいよね。
Everyone, it feels like Mon-Fa. It feels like it, feels like it.
そう、団長、ここ一言もね、モンスターファームって言葉出てないけど、
Yeah, Danchou didn't say the word Monster Farm once, but...
そう、いく、なんね、
yeah, we're going—
育成、育成してる、そういうゲームだから、強くするぺこ、ということで、じゃあ団長、
it's a game where you raise monsters, making Peko strong, so Danchou,
今回、あ、いきますね。
this time, ah, I'll go with it.
じゃあ、あお！
Then, blue!
モンスターファームで、お願いします！
Monster Farm, please!
やった！
Yay!
正直にモンスターファームのどの回かって言われたらわかんなかったかも
To be honest, if you asked me which episode of Monster Farm it was, I wouldn't have known.
7月3日のモンスターファームって言うのじゃなかったらね、わかんなかったけど、
If it hadn't said July 3rd's Monster Farm, I wouldn't have gotten it, but...
や、ありがとうございます。
Well, thank you very much.
あ、ちょっと1問だけ失敗しちゃったな。
Ah, I messed up just one question.
なんかゆれる。画面がゆれる。
It's shaking. The screen is shaking.
じゃあちょっと、あ、次にいけ、あ、待って。
Now then, let's move on to— wait.
あ、ほんまや、じゃあ、次のいきたいと思います。
Oh really? Okay, I'd like to move on to the next one.
じゃあ、みんなクイズありがとう。じゃ、マリーマは
Well, everyone, thanks for the quiz. Marie, as for you...
次ので、そう、あの、マリー、これから仲良くなっていこうね。
In the next one, yeah, Marie, let's get along better from now on.
団長、胸以外の女だって言われるようにするよ。
I'll make sure people say I'm a woman of more than just boobs, commander!
じゃあ、ちょっと団長お着替えしてこようかな。
Well then, I think I'll go change my clothes.
ちょっと次のコーナーに行く際にちょっと着替えてくるので、みんなちょっとお待ちください。ありがとう。
Since I'll be changing clothes before heading to the next corner, everyone please wait a moment. Thank you!
じゃあ、またね、ちょっと待っててね。
See you later, wait for me!
あはは！ ちょっとぎりぎり！ あぶねえ！
Ahaha! That was close! Phew!
着替えましたぞ！ みんな！
I've changed my clothes, everyone!
見えておりますか？
Can you see me?
いや、ちょっとみんなさ、あの、団長コメント見たけど、何？
Man, everyone, I saw your comments, but what?
みんな今日の夕飯何食べたとかさ、何雑談が始まったの？
What is this about what everyone ate for dinner today? Why did a chatting session start?
いやでも2声、なんか賑やかでね、いいなと思いました。
Well, but I thought it sounded lively and nice.
あと初見さんのコメントもあったんだけど、あの、来た瞬間なんかお着替え中になったんですけど、そういう配信ですかって書いてあったけど、そういう配信じゃないよ。
Also, there was a comment from a first-time viewer saying, 'As soon as I got here, it became a clothes-changing stream, is that what this is?' No, it's not that kind of stream!
いきなりね、そういう感じじゃありません。
It's not suddenly that kind of thing.
では、あの団長、どうしよう。衣装です。そう、アイドル衣装を着ております。
Now then, well, commander, what should I say? It's an outfit. Yes, I'm wearing an idol costume.
なんとね、今回、この可愛いアイドル衣装で、あの、撮影会をしたいと思います。
And you know what? This time, I want to hold a photo session in this cute idol costume.
で、今回はね、なんか、団長を撮ってくれる、その素敵なホロライブメンバーをちょっとお呼びしたので、
And this time, I've invited some wonderful Hololive members who will take pictures of me, so...
早速ゲスト、いいですか？呼んでくださいますでしょうか？
Shall we bring out our guests right away? Will you call them for me?
どっかな？呼んでくれるかな？
I wonder where they are? Will they call them?
あれだね、ちょっと
Let's see...
大丈夫かな？
Will this be okay?
なんか、こう、こう……ん？
Like, how should I... hmm?
どうしちゃった？あのさ、あのさ、あの……なんかこう、クリスマス一人の人、こ、あ……
What's wrong? You know, for people who spend Christmas alone... wh-, ah...
なんか持った。ほらよ。ひゅっ！え、歌うの？
I'm holding something. Here you go. Pew! Eh, am I singing?
どぅんどぅんどぅんどぅるん！ゲスト書いたから
Dun dun dun durun! Because I wrote 'Guest'!
うそ、ゲスト書いた？書いちゃった？
Wait, really? Did I write 'Guest'? I wrote it?
やだ、書かないでね！やめて、やめて！
No! Don't write that! Stop it, stop!
やだ！
No!
そうそうそう、そう、巨人の星、巨人の星がほしい！
Right, right, I want Star of the Giants!
そうそうそう、星、ひゅっ、ひゅっ、まだだけ、そうそうそうそうそう
Right, right, star, pyu pyu, not yet? Right, right, right.
巨人、なんか団長もこうやって巨人の星みたいにこう筋トレ……ちょっとやろうかな。ちょっとゲストさんが来るまでちょっと、よいしょ、しょ。
Giant... like, Danchou should also do muscle training like Star of the Giants... Let's do a little. Until the guest arrives, let's, heave-ho.
団長の好きなポイントとか先に言っとこうかな。ほら、冥想！
Maybe I should say Danchou's favorite points first. Look, meditation!
アイドル衣装に冥想って、なんかちょっと違和感バリバリなんだけど、
Meditation in an idol outfit feels super out of place, though.
かわいいじゃろ？これちょっとみんな好きになっちゃうじゃないかな、団長のこと。
Pretty cute, right? Won't everyone start loving Danchou because of this?
今、あれだよ！よろしければ今のうちに写真撮って、この白銀ノエル1周年でいっぱいツイートしてくださると嬉しいです。
Now, here's the thing! If you'd like, please take a picture right now and tweet a lot with #ShiroganeNoel1stAnniversary, I'd be so happy.
あれだよ！よろしければチャンネル登録と高評価もよろしくね！よろしくお願い……あっ、でも団長もね、久しぶりに来た、
And also, if you'd like, please subscribe to the channel and give a like! Please... Ah, but Danchou also came after a long time,
なんか最近ちょっと……
like, recently...
あっ！待って、あっ、巨人の星、待って、巨人の星の！やばい、ちょっとゲストさん来てくんねぇと団長マジでさぁ、
Ah! Wait, ah, Star of the Giants, wait, Star of the Giants! Oh no, if the guest doesn't show up soon, Danchou seriously...
巨人の星を目指しちゃうよ！団長、ぴょって、ぴょ。
I'll aim to become the Star of the Giants! Danchou, pyo, pyo.
なんか、でもね、団長ね、あの、小学校のときに初めてさ、あの野球したとき、あれなんだよ、剣道してたからね、こう、振っちゃうんだよな、こう。
Like, but you know, Danchou, when I first played baseball back in elementary school, you see, since I did kendo, I'd swing like this.
あっ、ゲストさん来てくれるみたいです！ちょっと、やな、これ。じゃあ、ゲストさん来てくれるみたいなので……来てくれますか？来てくれる？
Ah, looks like a guest is coming! Oh no, this. Well, since a guest is coming... will you come? Will you come?
あらっ、あっ、来た！あっ、あ、消えちゃった。それで私のこと結構いじってくれるかなと思ったけど、
Oh, ah, they're here! Ah, ah, they disappeared. I thought they'd tease me a bunch,
あ、これ、いいよ！もっとよ、メース！チョコ先セーイ！
Ah, this is good! More, mace! Choco-sensei!
あっ、叩いてくれるの、それで？あっ、いいよ！お尻だすよ、大丈夫？いいよ！
Ah, you'll hit it with that? Ah, sure! I'll stick my butt out, is that okay? Sure!
なんのもうなすこれ（笑）よかった！
What kind of eggplant is this? (Laughs) Yay!
よかった！じゃ、じゃあチョコ先生、何か写真ポーズしてとかあれば、いっぱい撮ってください。
Great! So, Choco-sensei, if there's any photo pose you want, please take a bunch of pictures.
えっ、いいんですか？なんでもいいんですか？
Eh, really? Anything is fine?
なんでもいいです。
Anything is fine.
あっ、そしたら、ちょっと私に片手を上げて、
Ah, in that case, raise one hand toward me,
片手を当てて、で、斜め右足かな？右足を斜め前に……ここか、ぐいっと。そうそう、出してもらって、それでカメラ目線で、
place one hand, and then, right leg diagonally? Put your right leg diagonally forward... right here, a good stretch. Right, right, put it out, and then with camera eye contact,
あ、ちょっとカメラさんの上から撮っていただいてもいいすかね？上、上目線がいいな。そうですね、そうですね、はい。
Ah, could you take it from above the camera? An upward gaze would be nice. That's right, that's right, yes.
そして……あっ、それときのがかわいい！やばいな、何をお説教しようとしてるんだチョコ先生！
And... Ah, that cute expression! Oh man, what kind of lecture are you trying to give, Choco-sensei!
それでちょっと前かがみになっていただいて、
And lean forward a little bit,
それで、ちょっとカメラにその頭に置いてる手を向けていただいて、「めっ」ていうポーズしてもらうの、ってもいいですかね？
and could you turn the hand resting on your head toward the camera and do a 'mep' pose?
殴っちゃうみたいになっちゃう！「めっ」てどういうこと？
It'll look like you're about to punch me! 'Mep'? What do you mean by 'mep'?
いいっすね、いいっすね！団長、メースでお仕置きしちゃうよ！
That's good, that's good! Danchou will punish you with her mace!
いや、ノエル団長にね、お仕置きされることなんてあんまりないすからね、マジで！まあ、よっぽどのことしない限り、団長ね、全肯定だから！全肯定人間だからね。
I mean, it's seriously rare to get punished by Noel Danchou! Well, unless you do something extreme, Danchou is totally affirming! She's a totally affirming person.
チョコ先生、ありがとうございます！
Choco-sensei, thank you very much!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
ありがとうございます！いや、チョコ先生も素敵なポーズ……ちょっと、メースでお仕置きされたいっていうのがマニアックだった、マニアックだったんですけど、
Thank you! Man, Choco-sensei's poses were wonderful... though wanting to be punished by a mace was quite manic, quite manic,
では、あと他にもね、来てくださるから、ちょっとお待ちしましょう。
Well, since others are coming too, let's wait a moment.
もしもし！
Hello!
この子や……団長！祭りだよ！祭り先輩！
This child... Danchou! It's Matsuri! Matsuri-senpai!
おめでとう！ありがとう！
Congratulations! Thank you!
祭り先輩のポーズ、ぴっ！かわいい！
Matsuri-senpai's pose, pyi! So cute!
いや、今日はね、ちょっと団長に、祭りちょっとシチュエーションやってほしくて……。シチュエーション？
I mean, today, I want Danchou to do a certain situation with Matsuri... A situation?
せっかくアイドル衣装なんで、ちょっとここが舞台設定として、まず団長が……
Since we're in idol outfits, as a stage setting, first Danchou...
色気を見せた状態でいて、
Maintaining an alluring pose,
カメラさんがちょっと団長のね上、あの男性的なこう目線。
the cameraman gives a sort of masculine gaze from above Danchou.
158cmだよね団長。
Danchou is 158 cm, right?
もうちょい…もうちょい。
A bit more... a bit more.
それで団長が振り返って、あ、お疲れ様です、これから頑張ってきますねみたいな感じのプロデューサーみたいなガチ恋距離で、
And then Danchou turns around and says, "Good work, I'll do my best from now on," in a hardcore love distance like a producer.
そう、プロデューサーだからさ俺。俺お願いしていいですか、ガチ恋距離でちょっと、
Right, because I'm the producer. Can I ask a favor? In a hardcore love distance, please...
はいではいきますね。
Okay, then I'll go.
そんな団長まで3、2、1、9。
Up to that Danchou... 3, 2, 1, cue!
お疲れ様です！団長これからも頑張ってきますね！
Great job! Danchou, I'll keep doing my best from now on!
ちょっとね団長ねこうゆう、小指タッチなんですけど、祭り先輩リング入れてくれますか？
And Danchou does this pinky touch thing... Matsuri-senpai, will you put a ring on it?
あ、もう入れます入れます！入れます！何個でも入れますねこれは。
Ah, I'll put it on! I'll put on as many as it takes!
あじゃ団長ちょっとこれ卒業ライブになっちゃう。よろしくお願いします。デュエットするんで祭りと。
Ah, Danchou, this is turning into a graduation live. Please take care of me. We're going to duet, Matsuri and I.
いや、ありがとうございます！めっっちゃ可愛かった！
Thank you so much! That was super cute!
改めておめでとう！ありがとう！
Congratulations once again! Thank you!
これからもよろしくだよ！よろしくおねがいします！だーいすき！ありがとう！大好きだよ！
Please keep taking care of us! Thank you, I love you so much!
団長も祭り先輩が好きだ！とくとくどく…
Danchou loves Matsuri-senpai too! Thump thump thump...
ありがとうちょっとルーナ姫に怒、ルーナ姫とかフーキングとかあと団長フレア、フレアにも怒られるようなことをしてしまった。あとチョコ先生もさっきコメントありがとう。
Thanks, I made Luna-hime mad... or rather, things that might make Luna-hime, Fu-king, Danchou Flare, and even Flare mad. And Choco-sensei commented earlier too, saying...
いや違うねこれ鳴雪ね鳴雪。ちょっと団長、どうしてもくすり指が、なんかちょっと、あれなんかも知れんね。ちょっと求めてるのかも知れん。
No wait, this is Nariyuki—no, Nariyuki. Danchou, somehow my ring finger... maybe it's just feeling that way. Maybe it's seeking something.
ちょっと小指がタッチゃう、小指じゃん、くすり指タッチゃうからさ、そうそうそう。
Because my pinky touches—no, not pinky, my ring finger touches, so yeah, yeah, yeah.
いやまだ、おっ？どどどどどどどどどどど…わ、ためちゃん！
Wait, still—oh? Wh-wh-wh-wh-wh... Watame-chan!
わためでーす！わためちゃんのポーズ。こうやね。叫んでる、おっ！
It's Watame! Watame-chan's pose. Like this. Screaming, oh!
いらっしゃい！お邪魔します！やってほしいのが、２つぐらいあるんで、
Welcome! Thanks for coming! There are about two more poses I'd like you to do,
じゃあわためちゃんおねがいしてもいいですか？オッケーです！なんだろう。
So Watame-chan, can I ask you? Okay! What could it be?
某モデルさんのポーズで、タッチのみたいな感じにこう寄せてもらって。はい、つま先。これは、もしや。
In a certain model's pose, bringing it close like a touch. Yes, tiptoes. Could this be...
つま先、これは、もしかして、ちょっとか、硬い！ふふっ。ち、そ、そうそうそう！あ、あ、あ、あ、団長ありがとうございます！
Tiptoes, could this be—wait, it's stiff! Haha. R-ri-right, right! Ah, ah, ah, ah, thank you, Danchou!
ここは、ここはちょっと見せる、あ、見たいけど…ふふっ。ちょっと、横、横の、100m？横がいいですね。横が。
Here, here I'll show a bit—ah, I want to see it, but... haha. A bit, side, side's... 100m? Side is good. The side.
いやこれマニアックだよ！まさかこのお題が来るとは！いややってくれたらのいいですか？なんだろう？うんうん。ちょっと脇を見せてほしいね。
This is so manic! I never expected this prompt! Is it okay if you do it? What could it be? Yeah, yeah. I want you to show your armpit.
ここに脇フェチが…チェッ、脇パインをちょっと見せて。どうどうでしょう？
There's an armpit fetishist here... Tch, show a bit of armpit pine. How is it?
いや、なんか団長普段で脇見せないから、そう脇見せないからなんかちょっと新鮮。あ、ちゃんとラインが、ラインがいいですね！このすっけべ羊が！
Well, Danchou doesn't usually show her armpits, so showing them feels kind of fresh. Ah, the lines are good! You lewd sheep!
この子は名誉な…うん。脇のラインがいいですね。ありがと。あ、お尻さんが出てしまいます。
This girl is honorable... Yeah. The armpit line is good. Thanks. Ah, your butt's showing out.
いやありがとう！こちらこそおめでとうございます！そう、優の羊って書かれてる。やったー！
Thank you! Congratulations to you too! Yeah, "Yuu's sheep" is written. Yay!
また遊んでください！遊ぼう！ありがとう！ありがとうございます！またね！
Please play with me again! Let's play! Thank you! Thank you very much! See you again!
いやわためちゃん…某ね、某、なんか…あ、くまちゃん！くまちゃんなんだっけ？
Watame-chan... a certain, a certain, something... Ah, bear-chan! What was bear-chan?
団長羊さんとくまちゃんだね、じゃあさっきのわためちゃんで。すごい色んな小物があるんだ。ぷしゅぷしゅ。みんな写真撮って、ぷしゅぷしゅ。でちゃんとから見るよ！ぷしゅぷしゅ。
Danchou, it's sheep-san and bear-chan, so like Watame-chan earlier. There are so many accessories. Pshu-pshu. Everyone take photos, pshu-pshu. And I'll watch properly from there! Pshu-pshu.
しかもポンポンついてる。くまちゃん。あ、あ、あ、あ、あ！おっ！やっぴー！やっぴー！やっぴー！おめでとう誕生日、やぴぴぴ！
Plus it has pompoms attached. Bear-san. Ah, ah, ah, ah, ah! Oh! Yappy! Yappy! Yappy! Happy birthday, yapipipi!
やっぴー！とわちゃんもね！めっちゃ可愛い！そう、誕生日おめでとうだよ！ありがとうございます！団長も1周年、いっ、いっ…おめでとうございます！ありがとう！
Yappy! Towa-chan too! Super cute! Yeah, happy birthday! Thank you! Danchou too, 1st anniversary, o-o-... Congratulations! Thank you!
やっ
Ya—
とわじゃもマイペースだから
Towa's always at her own pace too,
さっきね、ちょっとテストディスコしたときもなんかモグモグしながら
so earlier when we did a test Discord call, she was munching away...
で、だから、
And so,
バレてた？
Was I found out?
バレてるよ！
You totally were!
バレてるよと、
You've been caught!
やばいマイペースがそこでも出てしまってる、やばいですよ。
Man, my own pace is showing there too. That's bad.
え、とわちゃん何かポーズありますか？
Hey Towa, do you have any poses?
ちょっとやっぱりアイドルさんなんで、アイドルっぽいポーズがいいなと思って。
Since you're an idol, I thought an idol-like pose would be great.
まず、片足を曲げてほしいんですよね、ちょっと内側に。
First, I want you to bend one leg inwards slightly.
片足を曲げて
Bend one leg...
今まで結構あの、ズームが多かったから、全体な感じで内、内に曲げてほしいんです。
Up until now there's been lots of zoom, so bend it inwards overall.
内にか。
Inwards, huh?
これいかつい、こうか。
This looks tough. Like this?
違う、違う。あ、そうそうそうそうそうそう。
No, no. Ah, yeah, yeah, right there!
あ、そうそう。で、なんか、プリプリみたいなの。プリプリ？
Ah, right. And like, sort of cute and perky. Perky?
あ、そうそうそう。手をなんか、なんか外側にきゅ、みたいなの。
Yeah, yeah. With your hands kind of curved outwards like cute...
なんて言うの、難しいけど。そう。でも足がとりあえずその形だったらめちゃめちゃ可愛いんですよ。
How do I put it? It's hard. But if your legs are in that shape, it's super cute.
うんうん。
Uh-huh.
きゅきゅきゅ。
Cute, cute, cute.
かわいいね！
So cute!
いや、後ろもね、リボンがめちゃくちゃいいですね。かわいいこれ。後ろもかわいいの。
And the ribbon on the back is amazing. So cute. The back is cute too.
後ろもかわいい！
The back is cute too!
あ、本当に！リボン！
Oh, really! The ribbon!
そういうの、ちょっと足が内側みたいな感じのがちょっとアイドルっぽくってかわいいですよね。
Having the legs turned inward like that feels very idol-like and cute.
ちょっとこれ、勉強する。だってもアイドルのポーズね、よくわかっとらんから、ちょっととわちゃんに学びました。
I'll study this. Since I don't really know idol poses, I learned from Towa-chan.
これね、これ、あ、とわちゃん
This one, this one, ah, Towa-chan...
あ、そうそうそうそうそう。
Ah, yes, right there!
あ、でも待って、もう一回。
Ah, but wait, one more time.
こう。あ、そうそうそう。継続になっちゃった。
Like this. Ah, yes. It became continuous.
イエーイ！
Yay!
かわいいね。
So cute.
とわちゃん、やった。初めて、とわの帽子かぶったの。
Towa-chan, yay! This is the first time I've worn Towa's hat.
え、本当に？うれしい！
Eh, really? I'm so happy!
いや、写真撮ってね、みんな。ありがとう。
Make sure to take pictures, everyone. Thank you.
うれしい。とわそれ保存しよう。
I'm so happy. I'll save this.
うら！ありがとう。とわちゃんも忙しいのに、本当にお誕生日おめでとうだよ。
Yay! Thank you. Even though you're busy, happy birthday!
はーい、ありがとうございます。
Yes, thank you very much.
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday!
だって、お誕生日じゃないよ。
Wait, it's not my birthday.
あれ？ありがとうございます！
Huh? Thank you!
あれ、おめでとうございます！
Oh, congratulations!
ありがとう！なんかもう
Thank you! Man,
マイペースすぎんだよな、段取りも混乱した。
you're so at your own pace, it got the schedule all mixed up.
今のは、あ、誕生日おめでとうって言われて、ありがとうって気持ちか。
That was like, being told happy birthday and saying thank you.
なるほどな。
I see.
いや、でもとわちゃんの帽子とかもかぶれて、段取り幸せだった。嬉しいでございます。
Well, wearing Towa-chan's hat and everything made Dando happy. I'm so glad.
よいしょ。だってもハッピーバースデー、ま、一周年みたいなもんじゃん、誕生日みたいなもんですな。
Oof. Because it's a happy birthday, well, it's basically an anniversary, like a birthday.
そう、誕生日みたいなもんだよ。
Yeah, it's basically a birthday.
ちょっと誕生日、もしかして、今、うん、
Wait, a birthday? Could it be, right now, um...
ちょっと今、声は聞こえとるんかな？
Can you hear my voice right now?
ちょっと、だ、ちょっと、だ、ちょっと、なんだろう、興奮しちゃって、動きがピってなっちゃったから、ちょっと待っててね。
I got a bit too excited and my movements froze up, so please wait a second.
よし。いや、本当みんなありがとう。段取りね、ちょっと最近本当忙しくて、
Alright. Seriously, thank you everyone. Recently I've been really busy,
そう、配信とかもなかなかできてなくて、で、今回の3Dの、そう一周年のときも、
and haven't been able to stream much, so for this 3D anniversary,
ちょっとね、あの正直撮影会、どうしようみたいな思って、思ってたんだけど、
I was honestly wondering what to do about the photo shoot session,
でもどうしてもホロメンに来てほしいなと思って、
but I really wanted the holomen to come,
そう、急遽ね、昨日、そう、昨日、
so all of a sudden yesterday, yes, yesterday,
誰か、大丈夫？そう、誰か来てくれるかなみたいなことを、なんかちょっとね、あのホロメンのメンバーの全体にやったら、すぐピャッて来て、
I asked the hololive members if anyone could make it, and they came right away.
そうそうそうそう。本当にありがとうございました。
Yes, exactly. Thank you all so much.
そう、いや、みんな昨日はいっぱい配信したけど、段取りね、火曜日から、
Yeah, everyone streamed a lot yesterday, but Dando, from Tuesday...
あの、水木、水木ね、配信全然できてなかったんだよ、ホロラボとか。
Well, Wednesday and Thursday, I couldn't stream at all, like for Hololab.
そう、コラボとかぐらいしかできてなくて、ちょっと待ってね。段取りも、ちょっと今おからだから緊張しちゃって、多分筋トレで筋肉痛になってね、
Yeah, I could only do collabs and stuff. Wait a minute. Dando is nervous right now, probably got muscle aches from working out,
筋肉痛になって、ちょっと動かなくなっちゃったからちょっと待ってくださいね。
and my muscles are hurting so I can't move much, please wait.
今来たけど、どういう状況？
I just got here, what's going on?
今ね、ちょっと段取りが筋肉痛で、体がプルプルになってしまって、
Right now Dando has muscle aches and my body is all shaky,
そう、興奮しちゃって、ホロメンが来てくれてプルプルになってしまって、
yeah, I got so excited when the holomen came that I got all shaky,
ちょっとね、画面は待っててね、段取りの声で。
so wait for the screen, just listen to Dando's voice.
でも別に段取りの声だけでもね、みんな嬉しいよね。
Though everyone's happy just hearing Dando's voice, right?
段取り今動きもあってんだよ。あー、みんなに早く見せたいなって思いつつも、
Dando's moving around now too. Ah, while wanting to show everyone quickly,
筋肉痛で動けない。
I can't move because of muscle pain.
筋肉痛で動けてなていう。
Yeah, unable to move due to muscle pain.
ま、これが、まあ、あれだよね、生放送の逆に醍醐味だよ。
Well, this is sort of the true thrill of a live broadcast.
普通の動画だとこんなトラブルとかないから、
With normal videos there are no troubles like this,
みんな今一瞬一秒を今共有してるから、時間を。
so we're sharing every single second together right now.
本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
いや、でもよかったでも。ホロメンが来たあとで、よかったなと思います。
Well, but I'm glad. I'm so glad the holomen came afterwards.
そう、アクシデントも思い出ですからね。
Yeah, accidents are memories too.
思い出です。いや、もうスーパーストーンもたくさんありがとう。段取りね、待機の時から見てて、そのさ、
They're memories. And thank you so much for the super chats. Dando's been watching since the waiting room, and like,
カラフル虹色の
those colorful rainbow
スーパーチャットとかも見て、
super chats and everything...
自分では想像できなかったよ。
I couldn't have imagined it on my own.
こんなにね、たくさんの人に見てもらえるなんてさ、
To have so many people watching me like this...
本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
るーの3Dが、よろに見える？
It looks like Noel's 3D is "Yoro" (Night/Good)?
ちょっとね、これフォントの関係でさ、
Wait, that's because of the font.
3Dなんだけど、よろ、ま、どっちもいいよね、よろでも3Dでも。
It's 3D, but "Yoro"—well, either is fine!
いっしょいっしょ。
Together!
1周年おめでとうございます！
Happy 1st anniversary!
いつも応援、ありがと…ございます！
Always thank you so much!
そう、改めていっしょにね、おめでとうございます！ありがとうございます！
So let's celebrate together again, thank you!
いやちょっと筋トレしすぎたな、(笑)
Man, I did too many push-ups, haha.
ちょっと筋トレしすぎて体が、プルプルプルプル、ねえ。
I did too many push-ups and my body is trembling!
そう、よろ、よろ、終わりちょっと待っててね。
So, Yoro—Yoro, wait, hold on a second!
まだ団長、ちょっとやり残したことが、
Chacho (Leader), I still have something I forgot to do!
団長、まだやりな、やり残したことがあるんだけど、ちょっと待っててくれるか？
Chacho, I still have things I haven't done yet, so please wait a moment!
とりあえずね、絶対にやりたいことがある。
First of all, I definitely have something I want to do.
絶対にね、あの、サムネイルにも書いてあるんだけど、ちょっとね、言いたいことがありまして。
Definitely, um, it's also written on the thumbnail, but I have something I want to say.
そうそうそうそう。
So, so, so, so.
今の、今の見えたんかな？今いっしょ見えた。
Did you see it just now? I was the only one who saw it.
あ、見て！見て！みんな！
Oh, look! Look! Everyone!
あ、あ、え、え、あ、映ってないんですか？ちょっと待って。
Oh, it wasn't shown? Wait a minute.
あ、すみません、ちょっと一人で盛り上がってた！
Ah, sorry, I was getting excited all by myself!
あ、やっちゃった！あ、ちょっと待って、みんなちょっと待っててね。
Ah, I did it! Ah, wait a minute, everyone, please wait!
ちょ、みんなちょっと待っててね、今ね、みんなには見えてないらしい。ちょっと今すごい自分で、あの感動しちゃった。みんなには見えてな、ちょっと待ってて、待ってて、ごめんごめんごめん。
Everyone, please wait a minute! It seems it wasn't shown to everyone just now. I got too emotional by myself.
ちょっと待ってな、じゃあちょ、じゃあ、今のうちにちょっとカメラチェックしとこ。
Please wait a second, let me check the camera before that!
今のうちに。
In the meantime...
ちょっと待って、団長にはね、今あの動き始めたから、ちょっと待っててね、もうちょっとしたら
Wait, Chacho has started moving now, so please wait a little longer!
いけると思います。団長ね、どうしても言いたいことが3つほどあるからね、それだけは絶対に言いたいぞと、感じす。
I think you can. Chacho, no matter what, there are about three things I want to say, so I definitely want to say those!
団長1周年おめでとうございます！ありがと！
Chacho, happy 1st anniversary! Thank you!
改めて1周年おめでとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Once again, happy 1st anniversary! Thank you very much!
よししゃ、お姉さんボイスくだざい。
And now, Onee-san voice, please!
みなさま、こんばんはっす！
Good evening, everyone!
ホロライブ3期生白銀ノエルです。
Hololive 3rd Gen Shirogane Noel here.
みんなは、あの、いい子ちゃんだからね、待ってくれるね。
Everyone is, you know, a good girl, so please wait, okay?
よし、あ、じゃあちょっと、先に団長やりたいことをちょっとやらせてもらえるみたいなんできっと告知を先に出してもいいでしょうか？
Well then, since Chacho wants to say what she wants to say first, may I do the announcements first?
それでは、あの、早速あの3つあるんですけど、1つ目の告知から生かしていただきます。せーの、どん！
Then, let's start with the first announcement! Ready, don!
なんと、このあと21時から、そのみなとあくあ24時間配信があります。
And this coming 21:00, there will be a Minato Aqua 24-hour stream!
そして、あの、なんかみなとあくあ24時間配信は去年もね、あったんですけど、そのあくあ先輩の配信があって、
And, um, Minato Aqua's 24-hour stream happened last year too, and Aqua-senpai's stream is happening,
団長もね、あの、22時から、そう、あの出演させていただきますので、あの、ぜひぜひよろしくお願いします！このあと21時からあくあ先輩の配信始まりますので
and Chacho too, um, from 22:00, yes, is appearing, so please, please look forward to it!
いっしょに見ましょう。
Let's watch it together!
そしてね、22時もそうなんですけど、なんと、23時半からも、団長出演させていただくんですよう。
And, not only at 22:00, but at 23:30, Chacho is also appearing!
ま、団長っていうか、なんかね、このNDX、NDXって誰なんだろうの、いや誰のことなんか分からないんですけど、
Well, Chacho, or rather, this NDX—NDX? Who could that be? I don't really know whose it is,
なんかNDXさんがちょっと出るみたいなので、あの、土曜だって夜更かしも、見てください。そう、24時間企画の1つのコーナーでございます。
but it seems NDX-san is appearing, so please stay up late on Saturday to watch it! It's one of the corners of the 24-hour project.
では、次の告知に参ります。
Now, moving on to the next announcement!
どん！常闇トワお誕生日3D配信！そうなんかね、生誕アコースティックLIVEが、明日の8月9日22時から開始します。
Tokoyami Towa's Birthday 3D Stream! That's right, a "Seitan Acoustic LIVE" starting tomorrow, August 9th, at 22:00!
いやなんかね、本当は今日は誕生日だったんだけど、なんかこう、今日はこうやってね、その団長のこうとつ、というかね、撮影会に来てくれて、あの、トワちゃんは、そのご、こ野菜っていうのかな？そのこ野菜で、あの、アコースティックLIVEを開催するみたいなので、みなさん、明日もね、楽しみが続いておりますので、
Actually, today was supposed to be her birthday, but today she came to shoot with Chacho, and Towa-chan is holding an acoustic live for "Koyasai" (Vegetable Day? / Koyasai puns), so please look forward to tomorrow as well!
よろしくお願いします！トワちゃんもお誕生日おめでとう！3D楽しみです。うん。
Please look forward to it! Towa-chan, happy birthday! Have fun with your 3D!
そう。
Yeah.
8曲？8曲だってって書いてる。
It says 8 songs! 8 songs, she says!
8曲も歌うの？なんかちょ、ちょっと待って、トワちゃんもさ、鎧になってる。
She's going to sing 8 songs! Wait, Towa-chan is also getting all teary-eyed.
はい、では次の告知、これがい最後のご通知になります。
Okay, let's move on to the next announcement.
はい。
This will be the final one!
これはちょっとね、あの、これは私事になるんですけど、これ団長見えてるのかな？
This is, well, my own thing, but I wonder if Chacho's already shown it.
なんと、白銀ノエル1周年記念ボイスが8月8日本日20時50分から発売されました！
Guess what? Shirogane Noel 1st Anniversary Voice will be released today, August 8th, from 20:50!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
いや、待ってこれさ、ハッシュタグこれ、
Wait, is the hashtag shown?
これハッシュタグ見えとるんですが、これちょっとなんか、
The hashtag is shown, right? Wait, hold on.
ちょっとね、あの概要欄に、なんと載っておりますので、そう概要欄に載せておりますんでね、よろしくお願いします。
Well, it's listed in the description box, so please check the description box, okay?
さっきのはちょっと見てない。ちょっとね、あのゲスト出演でちょっと吹雪先輩が、出たんか知らんけど。
Wait, I didn't see the previous one. Ah, Fubuki-senpai made a guest appearance, which was funny.
ちょっとまあ、見てない見てないみんな、生放送特有の問題よ。
Well, you guys didn't see it either, right? That's a live broadcast exclusive problem!
で、本当こちらね、なんとボイス以外にも特典がありまして、ここにも書いてるんですけど、なんとね
And actually, this has, guess what, other benefits besides the voice! It's written here too,
あの団長、わたおじさんの
Also, for the chieftain Wata-otoko's
描き下ろしの、あのポスターカード、直筆サイン入れ入れます。
kakiyoro illustration, we're including a poster card with a direct autograph!
ま、なかなかね、直筆ってもう難しくなってきてる。
Well, lately, getting direct autographs has become really difficult,
だけど団長、今回は、今回もちょっとどうしてもということで、今回も直筆で書かせていただきます。
but chieftain, this time too, we've somehow managed it, so we're offering direct autographs again this time!
他にもね団長ね、なんと
And also, chieftain, look!
描きを、あの手描きの、それは、あれかな出ないのかな、それは、まちょっと概要欄で見てください。団長ね、自分で手描きした、あ、出た出た！ほら！そう手描きしたアクリルキーホルダーとか、
hand-drawn— ah, there it is, there it is! See? Hand-drawn acrylic keychains,
あとね丼、今回！
and a donburi bowl this time!
そう、団長おなじみのメンバーシップとかでもおなじみの丼がついてきますので
So, chieftain, just like the membership, we'll have our familiar donburi bowl included too,
よろしくお願いします。ちょっとアクリルキーはランダムになっちゃうんですけど、もしよければ、まどっちもなんかくらおさぶんとあと横にある栗と小豆瓶かっていう、
so please look forward to it. And the acrylic keychains will be random, but if you'd like,
もしよければ買ってくださると、レシレズ本当にぜひぜひ、あのASMR経由100で撮ったんでね、経由100ので撮ったASMRなのでボイスも特典グッズもぜひぜひ買ってくださると嬉しいです！よろしくお願いします！心を込めてアクリルキーホルダー作りました！
Really, I recorded the ASMR with a KU100 dummy head, so please buy both the voice and the bonus goods! I'd be so happy! Thank you for your support!
っていう感じでねちょっと告知になっちゃったんですけど、
So, that's all for the announcement,
ちょっとAqua先輩の配信が始まるんですが
but Aqua-senpai's stream is about to start.
ちょっと団長、あとごめんねちょっと一曲だけいいですか？
Chieftain, just one more song, is that okay?
Aqua先輩24時間配信頑張ってください！じゃ、Aqua先輩のそのエールも込めて歌います団長！みんなにも感謝の気持ちを込めて歌います！では聴いてください！
Aqua-senpai, good luck with your 24-hour stream! And Aqua-senpai, I'll sing with all my heart, dedicating it to you, chieftain, and expressing my gratitude to everyone! So please listen!
キラメキライダー☆
Kirameki Rider☆
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make the excitement of our birth resonate,
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
with the best time and the best companions!
キラメキに乗って☆
Riding on the sparkle☆
(イェーイ)
(Yeah!)
覚えているかな? 最初の歌 (懐かしいね)
Do you remember? Our very first song (how nostalgic),
私声が震えていた (ほんの少し)
My voice was trembling (just a little bit).
あの日から続く未来は
The future continuing from that day
みんなと掴んだ今日だよ
is today, which we've grasped together with everyone.
もっともっともっともっともっと 加速するハート
More and more, accelerating heart!
(いっしょに) 行くよ どこまでも
(Together) Let's go anywhere!
(are you ready?) 準備は OK?
(Are you ready?) Is your preparation OK?
ひらけ ! ! 夢 の トビラ を (123)
Open up the door of dreams! (1, 2, 3)
(キラメキライダー☆)
(Kirameki Rider☆)
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make the excitement of our birth resonate,
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
with the best time and the best companions!
ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
I'm here because you found me,
きみに会いたくてやって来たんだ
and I came because I wanted to see you.
みんなで歌おう
Let's sing together,
終わらないメロディ
an endless melody,
キラメキに乗って☆
riding on the sparkle☆
好きな気持ちカラフルに奏でたいな
I want to play my favorite feelings colorfully,
最高の場所 最高の仲間と
with the best place and everyone at my best.
ここにいるよ 幻なんかじゃない
It's no illusion,
きみのココロが幸せに染まるように
so that your heart is dyed with happiness,
重ねてくハーモニー
let's layer our harmonies!
キラメキまとって☆
Let's gather the sparkle☆
歌い続けたいな 踊り続けたいな
I want to keep singing, I want to keep dancing,
そんな願いやワガママもいいでしょ?
is such a wish or selfishness alright?
だって楽しくて!
Because it's just too much fun!
もう止まらない!!
It'll never stop!!
輝くステージで もっともっと!!
On this shining stage, more and more!!
(お願い) ずっと!!
(Please) forever!!
(オー) (イェーイ)
(Oh) (Yeah!)
嬉しい 楽しい 愛しい
Wonderful, happy, lovely—
だけじゃ語れない
words alone aren't enough.
今も今も悩みはあるけど
Even now, I still have worries, but
ここにいるよ 私ここにいるよ
I'm here, I'm right here,
きみと同じ世界を見つめて
looking at the same world as you.
(いくよ!) (キラメキライダー☆)
(Let's go!) (Kirameki Rider☆)
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's echo the newborn excitement
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
The best time with the best friends
キラメキに乗っけて☆
Riding on the sparkle☆
(イェーイ！)
(Yeah!)
覚えてるかな？ 最初の歌 (懐かしいね)
You remember? The first song (It's so nostalgic)
私 声が震えていた (ほんの少し)
My voice was trembling (Just a little)
あの日から続く未来は
The future that will continue from that day
みんなと掴んだ今日だよ
When I grabbed it with you all
もっともっともっともっと 加速するハート
More, more, more, more accelerating heart
(一緒に) 行くよどこまでも
Together, I'll go with you wherever you go
(are you ready？) 準備はok？
Are you ready? Preparation is OK?
ひらけ！！夢のトビラを (1 2 3)
Open up dream's door!! (1, 2, 3)
(キラメキライダー☆)
(Kirameki Rider☆)
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's echo the newborn excitement
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
The best time with the best friends
ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
I'm here because you found me
君に会いたくてやって来たんだ みんなで歌おう
I came all this way just to meet you, let's sing together
終わらないメロディ キラメキに乗っけて☆
Endless melody, riding on the sparkle☆
届いてるかな？ 私の声 (はっきりと)
I wonder if you can hear my voice (Clearly)
届けたいのは 君に笑顔 (そのスマイル！)
What I want to deliver is a smile to you (That smile!)
理想の遠さに悔しくて
I'm frustrated by the remoteness of my ideal
みんなと泣き笑ったね
I cried and laughed with you all
ぎゅっとぎゅっとぎゅっとぎゅっと 全部抱きしめて
I'll hug you all tightly, tightly, tightly, tightly
(一緒に) 行こうどこまでも
Together, let's go wherever you go
(are you ready？) 準備はok！
Are you ready? Preparation is OK!
すすめ！！希望の道を (1 2 3)
Come forward!! The path of hope (1, 2, 3)
(キラメキライダー☆)
(Kirameki Rider☆)
好きな気持ち カラフルに奏でたいな
I want to play my favorite feelings in a colorful way
最高の場所 最高ののみんなと
The best place with the best people
ここにいるよ 幻なんかじゃない
I'm here, this is not an illusion
君の心が幸せに染まるような
I want your heart to be dyed with happiness
重ねてくハーモニー キラメキ纏って☆
Overlapping harmonies, clad in sparkle☆
歌い続けたいな 踊り続けたいな
I want to keep singing, I want to keep dancing
そんな願い わがままでもいいでしょ？
Isn't it okay to wish and be selfish like that?
だって楽しすぎて！もうとまらない！！
I'm having so much fun!! I can't stop now!!
輝くステージで もっともっと！！ (お願いい) ずっと！！
On the shining stage, more and more!! (Please) forever!!
(オー！) (イェーイ！)
(Woah!) (Yeah!)
嬉しい 楽しい 愛しい だけじゃ語れない
I can't talk just because I'm happy, fun, and dear
今も今も悩みはあるけど
Even now, I still have a problem
ここにいるよ 私ここにいるよ
I'm right here, I'm right here
君と同じ世界を見つめてて
Looking at the same world as you are
(行くよ？) (キラメキライダー☆)
(Are we going?) (Kirameki Rider☆)
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's echo the newborn excitement
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
The best time with the best friends